# RAVINDRA BAKKAMANTHALA

Portfolio: https://ravindrabakkamanthala.github.io/ | LinkedIn: https://bit.ly/34J1iX8 |

Email:ravindrab240@gmail.com

#### About Me:

My Name is Ravindra Bakkamanthala, I am a Full Stack developer with around 9 years of experience in the Software Industry. I am a Constant Learner, Dedicated team player, Smart Coder, Innovative thinker and I love to take up challenging tasks and provide the best Output for my Customers.

#### **Technical Skills:**

- Java (Expert), Python (Intermediate), C (Basics)
- MySQL, Maria DB, Postgres, MongoDB (NoSQL), Hive, BigQuery, Aerospike, Redis
- GCP, AWS
- Airflow, PySpark, Dataproc, Cloud Functions
- Junit, Mockito, Cucumber, Karate

- JavaScript, Angular JS, Angular, React, D3, CSS, HTML
- Spring, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Struts, Vaadin
- Kafka, XACML, Elastic Search, Drools, AEM, Jenkins
- GIT, SVN

#### Other Skills:

• Multitasking, Team Player, Excellent ability in leading the team, Good Adaptability and Excellent Presentation skills.

#### **Education:**

Degree	Board	Year	CGPA	
Master's in Computer Engineering	University of Houston Clear Lake	2014	3.4	
B. Tech in Electrical and Electronics Engineering	JNTU-K, India	2012	7.4/10(CGPA)	

#### **Employment:**

## Wayfair | Senior Software Engineer | Austin, TX | Mar 2022 - Present

- Migrated the Wayfair Customer Information platform from Python to Java to achieve low latencies, Improvised the latency from p99 ~250ms to ~15ms, that supports 20k requests/sec.
- Improvised the Identity Customer Device Mapping platform that helped Recommendation Engine/ML platforms to show right preferences based on user device landings and events which in turn helped the platform to grow the revenue ~15 million dollars in North America.
- Migrated the storage from Hive to Native BigQuery as part of cost savings which saved +600k dollars per year for the company.

## SAP Labs | Senior Software Engineer | Newport Beach, CA | Dec 2020 – Mar 2022

- Developed Data Extraction Services to extract data from External S/4, TPM into SAP Cloud ITCM Landscape.
- Developed Cucumber Integration Tests for Microservices and incorporated in Jenkins's pipeline.
- Developed UI to Schedule and Manage the Data Extraction jobs using React.

## ATT Labs | Software Engineer | Middletown, NJ | April 2019 - Dec 2020

- Developed Log Parser streaming application which monitors the ansible logs and shows the live logs on GUI.
- Developed Workflow Process Engine to execute the workflow tasks using Spring Boot MicroService application.
- Developed Network Topology to Show the Network Configuration in Visualization form using D3 js.
- Developed Non-Open Stack Action implementations (Start/Stop/Restart/Configure) the VNF on fly Asynchronously.

## Verizon | Software Engineer | Piscataway, NJ | Dec 2018 - Mar 2019

 Migrated the Verizon My Business Portal Shopping Cart and Checkout Components (End to End) from AngularJS to Angular 7 and Monolithic to Microservices. • Lead the Offshore team and closely monitored the work on a day to day basis.

## ATT Labs | Software Engineer | Middletown, NJ | Feb 2015 - Dec 2018

- Developed the AT&T ECOMP Policy Engine from Scratch (Based on Research team POC).
- Developed the application using Vaadin Framework (GUI) and backend with Java Servlets and Python Modules.
- Migrated the complete application from Vaadin to AngularJS and Servlets to Microservices and used Hibernate for Dao Layer.
- Developed the Dynamic rendering Form Templates in GUI based on YML models.
- Open Sourced the application in 2016 as ONAP (Open Network Automation Platform).

# Cynosure Technologies LLC | Intern | Houston, TX | Dec 2014 - Feb 2015

- Developed Online Quiz tool portal for new hires assessment.
- Worked on fixing the issues related to the portal in the guidance of Senior developers.

# Personal and Free-Lancing Projects:

**GitHub:** <a href="https://github.com/ravindrabakkamanthala/">https://github.com/ravindrabakkamanthala/</a>

WebCrawler: The Application crawls the web pages and stores the metadata to the database for search optimization.

- Developed the web application with React Js to monitor and feed the urls from GUI.
- Developed the Crawler and Service with Spring Boot and both interacts with Mongo db and Redis.
- Service App will act as Queue on serving the URLs to crawler, and it monitors the urls which are already visited using Redis.
- Crawler App will fetch the metadata and add the href to Queue and store the metadata to the database.

## Portfolio Website: https://ravindrabakkamanthala.github.io/

• My Portfolio Application is developed using Angular 8, Bootstrap, Angular Material.

## Softworld Technologies: <a href="http://www.softworldtechnologies.com/">http://www.softworldtechnologies.com/</a>

- Designed and developed the Softworld Technologies company website from scratch.
- Developed the Frontend application using Angular 9.
- Developed the Backend Microservices using Spring Boot for managing the Jobs/Employees/Recruiters services.
- Developed the Email Notification System (Job Subscriptions/New Job Notifications/ Signup)
- Deployed the Application in AWS EC2.
- Used MySQL for storing the metadata related to website services.

# Thought Circuits: <a href="https://www.thoughtcircuits.com/">https://www.thoughtcircuits.com/</a>

- Designed and developed the Thought Circuits company website from scratch.
- Developed the Frontend application using React.
- Developed the Backend Microservices using Spring Boot.
- Deployed the Application in AWS EC2.
- Used MySQL for storing the metadata related to website services.